<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Some seasonable reflections upon the Quakers solemn protestation against George Keith's proceedings at Turner's-Hall, 29. Apr. 1697 Which was by them printed, and sent thither, as the reasons of their not appearing to defend themselves. Herein annex'd verbatim. By an impartial hand.</title>
            <author>Leslie, Charles, 1650-1722.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 56 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A47769</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99831791</idno>
  <idno type="VID">36258</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240941456</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing L1159</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R220387</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99831791</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99831791e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A47769)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 36258)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2127:10)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Some seasonable reflections upon the Quakers solemn protestation against George Keith's proceedings at Turner's-Hall, 29. Apr. 1697 Which was by them printed, and sent thither, as the reasons of their not appearing to defend themselves. Herein annex'd verbatim. By an impartial hand.</title>
                  <author>Leslie, Charles, 1650-1722.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 14 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for Charles Brome, at the Gun at the west end of St. Pauls,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1697.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>An impartial hand = Charles Leslie.</note>
                  <note>"A solemn protestation against George Keith's advertisement, arbitrary summons and proceedings against certain persons, and a meeting of the people called Quakers" has caption title on p. 1; "Some reflections upon the foregoing protestation" has caption title on p. 3; register and pagination are continuous.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Cambridge University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">Keith, George, 1639?-1716 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Society of Friends --  England --  Controversial literature --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Quakers --  England --  Controversial literature --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>John Latta </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:36258:1"/>
            <p>Some Seasonable REFLECTIONS UPON THE Quakers SOLEMN PROTESTATION Against <hi>George Keith</hi>'s Proceedings at <hi>TURNER'S-HALL,</hi> 29. <hi>Apr.</hi> 1697.</p>
            <p>Which was by them <hi>Printed,</hi> and sent thither, as the <hi>Reasons</hi> of their not Appearing to Defend Themselves. Herein Annex'd <hi>Verbatim.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>By an Impartial Hand.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>Charles Brome,</hi> at the <hi>Gun</hi> at the west end of St. <hi>Pauls,</hi> 1697.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="treatise">
            <pb facs="tcp:36258:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:36258:2"/>
            <head>A Solemn <hi>PROTESTATION</hi> against <hi>George Keith</hi>'s Advertisement, Arbitrary Summons and Proceedings against Certain Persons, and a Meeting of the People called <hi>Quakers.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>WHereas the said <hi>G. K.</hi> a Scotchman, has assumed to himself a Power and Authority to Erect several Meetings of the Nature of some strange and new Court of Judicature at <hi>Turner's-Hall, London,</hi> one on the Eleventh of the Month called <hi>June,</hi> 1696. and another on the 29th. of this present Month called <hi>April,</hi> 1697. (under pretence of having the <hi>Permission of the Civil Authority, that he is further to Detect the Vile and Gross Errors and Heresies of certain</hi> Persons by Name, and a Meeting of the People called <hi>Quakers</hi>) unto which he hath Cited or Summoned them, to <hi>hear themselves Re-charged, and Prov'd Guilty thereof,</hi> as being <hi>Repugnant to the Great Fundamentals of the Christian Religion</hi> (which Charges of his, as perversly Stated by him, are Expresly Denyed by us) for Proof thereof, Refer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring to his own Printed <hi>Advertisement</hi> and <hi>Narrative,</hi> which have been largely Answe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red in Print, he having begun the Controversie with us, by Printing divers bitter In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vectives against us, expresly Contrary to his own former Testimonies in Print; and divers of our Friends Books, in Answer to him, still lie heavy upon him, unreply'd to. And seeing he cannot Effect his Invidious Designs in Print, to make his Odious Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racter of <hi>Heresie, Spreading Gangreen, and Contagion,</hi> &amp;c. take Effect against us, he has Presum'd to Erect such an Arbitrary Course of Judicature, in a Confused Meeting at <hi>Turners-Hall,</hi> and thereunto, in his own Name and Authority, to Summon the Persons and Meeting, as aforesaid, without their Privity, Concurrence, Consent or Agreement thereunto; either as to the Time, Place, Terms or Propositions, but he is the Sole Imposer.</p>
            <p>We therefore, who are Concern'd in behalf of the Peaceable People called <hi>Quakers,</hi> both as Free-Born English-Men and Christians, do deny, and Solemnly Testifie against the Usurpation, Arbitrary and Irregular Proceedings of the said <hi>G. K.</hi> and against his new Jurisdiction (assum'd by him) for the same Reasons, which were Exhibited in Print the last Year, <hi>Why the People called</hi> Quakers <hi>Refused their Appearance at his Perem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ptory Summons</hi> (and therefore he had no Reason to Expect their Appearance this Year, the more Insincere he, in his new Summons) and more particularly,</p>
            <p n="1">1. Because he has no Legal Power to Erect any such new Court of Judicature, and therein set himself up as Judge, and Publickly to Stage, Brand, and Condemn Peace<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able Protestant Subjects, and that in their Absence too, (who are also Free-Born Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lish-Men) as <hi>Hereticks,</hi> &amp;c. and thereby to Endeavour to Expose them to the Scorn, Contempt and Rage of a mixt Multitude, who are unmeet to Judge of Religious and Spiritual Matters, or Controversies.</p>
            <p n="2">2. We do not believe the Civil Authority, or any Concerned therein, on Due Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sideration; or Just Information, will Countenance or Permit such an Usurp'd Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity, or Pernicious President, as the said <hi>G. K.</hi> has Assum'd and Attempted in this Case; tending, not only to Discord, Divisions, Heats, Animosities and Tumults, but to Invade the just Liberties of Free-Born English-Men (who are Peaceable Protestant Subjects,) and to Gratifie and Strengthen the Popish Interest, that they may Glory in such Divisions and Disorders, made by Turbulent Incendiaries.</p>
            <p>We are not Unsensible, that some Officious and Envious Agents are in the bottom of this Turbulent Attempt; who, altho' they may pretend to be Reformed Protestants, yet savour too much of a Popish Persecuting Spirit, (Justly Complain'd of by Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stants) and whose Work tends to bring an <hi>Odium</hi> upon the Protestant Religion.</p>
            <p n="3">3. We presume the said <hi>G. K.</hi> can Produce no Legal Commission from the Civil Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority, either by Act of Parliament, or under the Great Seal of <hi>England, Annually</hi> to Erect and hold his said Court of Judicature, to Summon, Convict and Condemn <hi>Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers</hi> (so called) or any other Free-Born English-Men, or Protestant Subjects for <hi>Heresie</hi> or <hi>Hereticks,</hi> who are contrariwise Legally Recognized.</p>
            <p n="4">4. His feigned and false Pretence of <hi>Justly Desiring</hi> the Persons and Meeting aforesaid to be present (<hi>i.e.</hi> to hear themselves <hi>Recharged,</hi> Convicted and Condemn'd of <hi>Vil<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> and
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:36258:3"/>
               <hi>Gross Heresies,</hi> &amp;c.) appears, not only a peremptory Summons, but his Noise of <hi>Vile</hi> and <hi>Gross Errors,</hi> and <hi>Heresies, spreading Gangreen and Contagion,, Infecting many Thousands in these Three Nations,</hi> &amp;c. does much Resemble the Popish Clamours and Calumnies against Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>testant Martyrs, and then <hi>away with them, cut them off;</hi> and Fire and Faggot followed, when the Writ <hi>de Haeretico Comburendo,</hi> and the Six Bloody Articles were in Force, 31. <hi>H.</hi> 8. Ch. 14. both which are justly and happily Repeal'd.</p>
            <p n="5">5. For the same Reasons, which the Parliament gave in the 16th. Year of K. <hi>Charles</hi> I. against the <hi>Court of Star-Chamber,</hi> and <hi>High-Commission-Court</hi> (Ch. 9. 10.) and for taking away, and dissolving the same (tho' these had more Face of Authority, than this of <hi>G. Keith</hi>'s) we Oppose, Deny and Protest against these his Irregular and Arbitrary Procee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dings and his new Court of Judicature, and Usurped Power and Authority therein, as (not only tending to Discord, Disorder, and Persecution, and Endangering the Publick Peace, but also) Repugnant to the <hi>Great Charter, Fundamental Laws (and Liberties of</hi> Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land) Providing <hi>that no Free-Man shall be Condemned, or any way Destroyed</hi> without <hi>due Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of Law;</hi> as well as expresly contrary to the Intent and Tenor of the late Act of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, made in the first Year of the Reign of K. <hi>William</hi> and Q. <hi>Mary,</hi> Entituled, <hi>An Act for Exempting their Majesties Protestant Subjects Dissenting from the Church of</hi> England, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> made <hi>for the Ease of Scrupulous Consciences in the Exercise of Religion, as an Effectual Means to Unite their Majesties Protestant Subjects in Interest and Affection.</hi> And the Meeting-Places thereby Permitted or Allow'd and Recorded, being for <hi>RELIGIOUS WORSHIP,</hi> as in the said Act is Expressed, Consequently, not for Division, Discord or Stages of Conten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; and therefore we are not free, either as Men or Christians, to Subject our selves to any such Irregular Summons, or Arbitrary Power and Usurpation, as aforesaid.</p>
            <p n="6">6. <hi>Heresie</hi> having been made an High Crime in Law [<hi>Mirror, Justices,</hi> p. 16.] and high<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Punishable, <hi>G. K.</hi>'s Publickly Staging and Branding us as <hi>Hereticks,</hi> appears both an High Defamation, and tending to Destroy us in our Reputations and Liberties also, both contrary to Law and Gospel, and to Introduce a new and severe Persecution to Gratify his Envy. For his Turbulent, Persecuting Spirit and Apostacy, from Christian Chari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, Meekness and Moderation, and from that Faith that Works by Love, sufficiently appear; also by his <hi>Earnest Expostulation with the most Pious and Learned of the Church of</hi> England (as Flatteringly he Terms them) to Incense both the Clergy and Civil Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity against us, in his Printed Postscript to his <hi>Antichrists and Sadducees,</hi> and therein Commending the Popish Watch-Men of <hi>Rome,</hi> and <hi>Popish Countries,</hi> above <hi>most among the Protestants,</hi> for their Zeal against such <hi>Antichristian Errors and Heresies,</hi> as he there would make the World believe, Quakers hold <hi>much worse than the worst of Popery</hi> (p. 40, 41.) and his Summoning and Condemning us as <hi>Hereticks,</hi> appears so much Resembling the Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctice of some of his Country-Men of the <hi>Presbytery,</hi> to Incense the Rabble or Mob against our Friends in <hi>Scotland,</hi> as they have of late shamefully done, both in <hi>Glasgow</hi> and <hi>Edenborough,</hi> to the Great and Barbarous Abuse of our poor harmless Friends in those Parts, by their bitter Clamours and Aspersions against them, as <hi>Hereticks,</hi> &amp;c. That we humbly hope, the Civil Protestant Government of <hi>England</hi> will never Countenance or Permit such unwarrantable Usurpation, which is not to use only <hi>Spiritual Weapons</hi> (as he pretends) but is of a contrary Nature and Tendence. We having treated the said <hi>G.K.</hi> at many Select and Solemn Meetings, we have had with him, in all Christian Patience and Tenderness on our parts; which were Slighted and Rejected by him. Thus we have Answer'd his <hi>Advertisement</hi> and <hi>Summons, ad hominem,</hi> as Peaceable, Free-Born English-Men, whose present Liberty ought not to be Invaded or Disquieted, either by any Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitrary Usurpation, or Contentious Irreligious Meetings, whose End is to Asperse and Abuse others: Nor may such, with safety, be Imitated, Allowed or Abetted by any of different Perswasions.</p>
            <p>Now, let it be observed, whatever may happen to be the Effects or Consequence of the said <hi>G. K.</hi>'s Disorderly and Unwarrantable Proceedings, or Meeting aforesaid, we have given out this Solemn Protestation against the same, to Manifest our own Inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cency and Clearness therefrom.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>Written, in Behalf of the People<lb/> called</hi> Quakers, <hi>by some of<lb/> them Concerned.</hi>
               </signed>
               <dateline>
                  <date>
                     <hi>London,</hi> the 26th. Day of<lb/> the 2<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> Month, 1697</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="commentary">
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:36258:3"/>
            <head>Some <hi>Reflections</hi> upon the foregoing <hi>Protestation.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>IT has been the common Custome of the <hi>Quakers,</hi> since their first appearing in the World, to provoke others to Disputes, and to An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>swer all <hi>Challenges</hi> sent to them for that purpose, as desiring nothing more than the occasion of <hi>Vindicating</hi> and <hi>Propagating</hi> their <hi>Princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples</hi> in the Face of the World. They readily embrac'd the Invitation of the <hi>Baptists</hi> to a publick Disputation at <hi>Barbican;</hi> and after gave them the <hi>Challenge,</hi> and had their Tryal of skill at their <hi>Meeting-place</hi> in <hi>Wheeler-street;</hi> and after printed their <hi>Conferences.</hi> They had frequent <hi>Disputes</hi> with Mr. <hi>Baxter,</hi> and several others. But these two years past, they have alter'd their Method; they are grown more <hi>sedate</hi> and <hi>modest,</hi> or they find their <hi>Cause</hi> not so <hi>Tenable</hi> as formerly they thought it; and rail at <hi>G. Keith</hi> for bringing them now to the like <hi>Test.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>They patiently endur'd his printed <hi>Challenge</hi> to them last year, to meet him at <hi>Turners-Hall,</hi> and justifie their <hi>Doctrines.</hi> Some of their number went thither, and made some opposition, but without any Deputation, as they said, from the Body of the <hi>Quakers.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This year they have received another <hi>Challenge</hi> from him, to the same purpose, to which the foregoing <hi>Protestation</hi> is all the <hi>Answer</hi> they return'd; and suffer'd him to produce his <hi>Charges</hi> of gross <hi>Heresies</hi> against them, before the <hi>Auditory</hi> there Assembled, without any other opposition.</p>
            <p>Therefore this their <hi>Protestation</hi> and whole <hi>Defence</hi> ought seriously to be consider'd, which I will do without <hi>Passion</hi> or <hi>Ill-words,</hi> other than when I am forc'd to repeat some of theirs. For,</p>
            <p>The design of the following <hi>Reflections</hi> is only to bring the <hi>Quakers</hi> to a thorow <hi>Conviction</hi> of their <hi>Errors;</hi> and to such an <hi>Acknowledgment</hi> and <hi>Confession</hi> of them, as is indispensible to a true <hi>Conviction.</hi> There is no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing more desir'd of them than to <hi>Retract</hi> and <hi>Disown</hi> what is prov'd to be faulty in their <hi>Writings;</hi> and such <hi>Faults</hi> as are either destructive to the <hi>Faith,</hi> or <hi>Scandalous</hi> (and so <hi>sinful</hi>) to the <hi>Reputations</hi> of their <hi>Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours,</hi> in giving <hi>false</hi> and <hi>uncharitable Representations</hi> of them. And this they are oblig'd to do by all the Rules of <hi>Christianity,</hi> it being the smal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lest <hi>Satisfaction</hi> that they can make, to repair (so far at least) the <hi>Inju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries</hi> thereby done to the <hi>Christian Doctrine;</hi> and to the <hi>good Name</hi> of those whom they have wrongfully <hi>Traduced.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:36258:4"/>
            <p>But this <hi>Protestation</hi> shews how unwillingly they are brought to either. By their shifting and strain'd Excuses for not appearing in their own De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence. As in the first line, that <hi>G. Keith</hi> is a <hi>Scotch-man.</hi> Again, p. 2. That his design is to <hi>gratify the Popish Interest;</hi> and that there are un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der-hand <hi>Officious and Envious Agents, whose work tends to bring an Odi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>um upon the Protestant Religion.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But these deserve no Answer, <hi>being</hi> but <hi>Clamours;</hi> and as groundless as his, who call'd his Resty Horse <hi>Popishly affected.</hi> For the <hi>Detection</hi> of the <hi>Quakers</hi> by <hi>Protestants,</hi> is so far from bringing any <hi>Odium</hi> upon the <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>testant Religion,</hi> that it is the only Method to preserve the <hi>Protestant Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion</hi> from the <hi>Scandal</hi> that must unavoidably fall upon it, if the <hi>Quakers</hi> are allow'd to come under that Denomination. For then must we own them as <hi>Protestants,</hi> who have thrown off the <hi>Sacraments,</hi> and all out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward <hi>Priesthood</hi> and <hi>Ordinances;</hi> nay, who deny the <hi>Holy Trinity;</hi> the <hi>Divinity</hi> of that Man, <hi>Jesus</hi> our Lord, or <hi>Redemption</hi> by his Blood <hi>out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardly</hi> shed; the <hi>Resurrection</hi> of the <hi>Body;</hi> or a Final and outward <hi>Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> at the end of the World. Then, are they good <hi>Protestants</hi> who esteem the <hi>Bishops,</hi> and <hi>Church</hi> of <hi>England</hi> to be <hi>Baal</hi>'s <hi>Priests, Conjurers,</hi> nay very <hi>Devils.</hi> Can <hi>they</hi> and <hi>we</hi> both be <hi>Protestants?</hi> What a Notion will this beget of <hi>Protestancy!</hi> How <hi>Involv'd</hi> and <hi>Self-contradictious;</hi> How <hi>Contemptible</hi> and <hi>Odious</hi> will this render the Name of <hi>Protestant</hi> to all the World! Will not this <hi>Latitude</hi> bring <hi>Socinians</hi> and <hi>Deists;</hi> even <hi>Maho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>met</hi> and the very <hi>Heathen</hi> within the Pale of the <hi>Protestant Communion!</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Therefore it is absolutely necessary, either that we shou'd renounce the Name of <hi>Protestants,</hi> or no longer Comprise the <hi>Quakers</hi> within that <hi>Pale:</hi> That is, unless they can <hi>fully</hi> and <hi>clearly</hi> Justifie their <hi>Ancient Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stimonies</hi> as to these things objected against them, or otherwise, now at last, freely <hi>Disown</hi> and <hi>Condemn</hi> them.</p>
            <p>Till they shall be brought to do one of these, 'tis in our own Defence that we Dispute against them; and they cannot brand this with the Ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nominious Names either of <hi>Severity</hi> or <hi>Persecution.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>They are the <hi>Aggressors.</hi> They have <hi>Attack'd</hi> our <hi>Religion</hi> in all the Parts of it; our <hi>Bishops</hi> and <hi>Clergy,</hi> and our whole <hi>Constitution.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And we require no greater amends, for all that they have done against us, than to say, That they are <hi>sorry</hi> for it, and have done us wrong; and that they will no longer stand by those who have sought and endeavour'd our <hi>Ruin.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And tho' they shou'd refuse us even this <hi>Justice,</hi> and <hi>Reasonable Secu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity</hi> for the future; yet we press for no <hi>Persecution</hi> against them; for no <hi>Fines</hi> or <hi>Imprisonments:</hi> But only, that we shou'd not be oblig'd to ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledge them as true <hi>Protestants,</hi> and that we may have <hi>Liberty</hi> to justifie our selves, and our <hi>Religion</hi> against the grievous <hi>Calumnies</hi> with which they have <hi>loaded</hi> both.</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:36258:4"/>
            <p>And if this be refus'd to us, the Cry of <hi>Persecution</hi> will run on our side. For, what greater or more unjust <hi>Persecution</hi> can there be, than to compel Men to lye still under the severest <hi>Reproaches,</hi> and debar them from the <hi>Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vilege</hi> due to the greatest <hi>Offenders,</hi> to make any <hi>Defence,</hi> or so much as a <hi>Complaint</hi> of their <hi>Sufferings,</hi> however <hi>undeserv'd!</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Is it no <hi>Persecution</hi> of the <hi>Tongue</hi> for the <hi>Quakers</hi> to represent our <hi>Clergy</hi> as the <hi>Vilest</hi> and most <hi>Odious</hi> of <hi>Mankind;</hi> as an <hi>Abominable Tribe,</hi> the <hi>Bane</hi> of <hi>Soul</hi> and <hi>Body,</hi> &amp;c. And do they call it a <hi>Persecution</hi> in us so much as to <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>member</hi> or <hi>Repeat</hi> the <hi>Epithets,</hi> which they have given us, and which they still refuse to <hi>Retract;</hi> for (as said at first) that is all which is desir'd of them. But now let us consider their <hi>Protestation.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Page 1. It refers to their <hi>Answers</hi> in print, particularly to <hi>G. Keith</hi>'s <hi>Narrative,</hi> and says, that they are yet <hi>unreply'd</hi> to, whereas that <hi>Answer</hi> to the <hi>Narrative</hi> has been Reply'd to in <hi>Satan Disrob'd,</hi> which is yet <hi>unreply'd to,</hi> ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept in <hi>G. Whitehead</hi>'s carping at some Passages in it, in his pretended <hi>Answer</hi> to <hi>The Snake in the Grass. ibid.</hi> He says they were summon'd without their <hi>Privity;</hi> that is false, for they had notice in print about a Month before. But it was without their <hi>Consent</hi> or <hi>Agreement,</hi> that's true, for they wou'd never <hi>Consent</hi> to have their Errors expos'd. This is the Plea (if it wou'd be admitted) of all <hi>Guilty</hi> Persons, who do not <hi>Consent,</hi> or <hi>Agree,</hi> to be brought to Justice, or to have their Crimes Detected. But, if they were Innocent, they wou'd desire to clear themselves.</p>
            <p>As to their <hi>Reasons</hi> held forth in their <hi>Protestation.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="1">I. <hi>First,</hi> They operate in every Article as strongly against their publick Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putations with the <hi>Baptists</hi> at <hi>Barbican, Wheelers street,</hi> &amp;c. Their coming into Churches in time of Divine Service, and provoking the Priests to Dispute with them; against the whole method of their own first setting up, and all their man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner of Proceeding since. 2dly, The Meeting appointed at <hi>Turners-Hall,</hi> 11 <hi>June</hi> last, and this 29 <hi>April</hi> was no <hi>Court of Judicature,</hi> nor any <hi>Court</hi> at all, only for the Information of who pleas'd to be present, and to have gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven the <hi>Quakers</hi> an opportunity to vindicate themselves, if they thought themselves misrepresented; and which it's not to be doubted but they wou'd have done, if they thought they cou'd have done it. For, why wou'd they, who have sought, and even forc'd, all opportunities to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>commend their Doctrine, refuse such an occasion that was offer'd to them? and to have done it with so great Advantage, in the face of the Nation? not only to Establish their own Doctrine, but to overthrow their Opponents? and that with so much the more Advantage, that it was at the Instance of their Adversaries, and by their provocation? But their Pleading that they are <hi>Free-born English Men</hi> to excuse it, is Pleading <hi>Guilty</hi> in a very foolish and shameful manner. And their ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jecting that <hi>G. K.</hi> had no <hi>Legal Power</hi> for what he did, was Condemn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of <hi>G. Fox</hi> and all the <hi>Quakers,</hi> who never so much as pretended to
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:36258:5"/> any <hi>Legal Power</hi> for all their <hi>Oppositions</hi> and <hi>Disputations,</hi> which were in direct contradiction to the <hi>Legal Powers,</hi> and by an Authority (as they pretended) far superior to all <hi>Legal Powers</hi> upon Earth; and by which they took upon them to declare the <hi>Laws</hi> null and of none effect, as in case of <hi>Tythes,</hi> of maintaining an outward <hi>Priest-hood,</hi> &amp;c. But more e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>specially as to their Discipline of the <hi>Second days Meeting,</hi> of their <hi>Month<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, Quarterly,</hi> and <hi>Yearly Meetings,</hi> which are direct <hi>Courts,</hi> and of <hi>Judi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cature</hi> too; for therein they grant <hi>Orders,</hi> inflict <hi>Censures,</hi> as of <hi>Excom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munication</hi> against <hi>G. Keith,</hi> &amp;c. Have <hi>Deputies</hi> and <hi>Representatives</hi> from all the Counties of <hi>England,</hi> and from other parts of the World.</p>
            <p>But they have herein started a very material Question, which ought to be ask'd of them in their own words, viz. <hi>What Legal Power they have to E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rect any such new Courts of Judicature, and therein set up themselves as Judges</hi> (which <hi>G. K.</hi> did not at <hi>Turners Hall,</hi> but left it to the Auditors to Judge for themselves) <hi>and publickly stage, brand, and condemn peaceable Protestant Subjects</hi> (i. e. both the <hi>Church of</hi> England, <hi>and</hi> Dissenters) <hi>and that in their absence too (who are also Free born</hi> English <hi>Men) as Hereticks;</hi> (nay more, as <hi>Devils Incarnate, Baal's Priests, Dogs, Wolves, Conjurers,</hi> &amp;c.) <hi>And thereby to endeavour to expose them to the scorn contempt and rage of a mix'd mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titude, who are unmeet to Judge of Religious and Spiritual Matters or Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>troversies?</hi> And this connot come within the <hi>Act</hi> of <hi>Toleration,</hi> which is only for <hi>Religious Worship;</hi> and its expresly caution'd, that it shall be with their <hi>Doors open,</hi> that all may have liberty to come in and hear; otherwise they forfeit all the Priviledges of that <hi>Act.</hi> Now at the <hi>Meetings</hi> before men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion'd, they have their <hi>Doors</hi> shut, and <hi>Door-keepers</hi> at them, to keep out all them they think fit not to admit; and their Business is <hi>Government</hi> and <hi>Discipline,</hi> which is no ways within the <hi>Act,</hi> and comes under the penalty of all those <hi>Laws</hi> which prohibit all <hi>Convocations, Meetings, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sultations,</hi> &amp;c. without the <hi>King</hi>'s Licence; much more to <hi>Enact, Promul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gate,</hi> or <hi>Decree</hi> any <hi>Orders</hi> or <hi>Constitutions</hi> whatsoever. Now, if the <hi>Bi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>shops</hi> and <hi>Clergy</hi> of <hi>England,</hi> tho' Recogniz'd and Establish'd by the <hi>Law,</hi> wou'd incur a <hi>Premunire</hi> so much as to <hi>meet, consult,</hi> or <hi>debate,</hi> tho' con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning only their own <hi>Order</hi> and <hi>Spiritual</hi> Jurisdiction, without the <hi>King</hi>'s Licence; How then have the <hi>Quakers</hi> this Authority; and freely, and yearly, nay <hi>Weekly</hi> exercise it without controle! Further, if when the <hi>Clergy</hi> do meet in <hi>Council, Convocation,</hi> or <hi>Synod,</hi> the <hi>King</hi> may have his <hi>Commissioner</hi> present, to inspect, and even to regulate their Proceedings, that nothing may be there Transacted prejudicial to the Government: How much more reasonable is it, that tho' the Quakers <hi>Convocations</hi> or <hi>Synods</hi> were tollerated by Law, yet that the <hi>King</hi> shou'd have his <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners</hi> there to inspect their Proceedings, and give an account of their Debates? If <hi>Christian Emperors</hi> and <hi>Kings</hi> have had their <hi>Ambassadors</hi> and <hi>Ministers</hi> present in the <hi>General Councils:</hi> If the <hi>Hugonots</hi> in <hi>France</hi> have submitted, nay desired and requested to have the <hi>King</hi>'s <hi>Commissio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners</hi> present in those <hi>Synods,</hi> which by His Majesties Grace and Favour,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:36258:5"/> they have been suffer'd to hold, that the <hi>Government</hi> might not only be secur'd from any Attempts of theirs, but all <hi>Fears,</hi> or so much as <hi>Jea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lousies</hi> taken away. If the <hi>Presbyterians</hi> in <hi>Scotland,</hi> tho' now Estabished as the National Religion, have the like <hi>Commissioner</hi> present in their <hi>Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral Assemblies,</hi> why shou'd not the <hi>Quakers</hi> be oblig'd to receive a <hi>Commissioner</hi> from the <hi>Government</hi> into the <hi>Second-days, Monthly, Quarter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly,</hi> at least into their <hi>Yearly Meetings?</hi> If at their beginning they were too inconsiderable for the notice of the Government, they are now become a <hi>Numerous,</hi> a <hi>Wealthy,</hi> and a <hi>Potent</hi> People; and in all respects worthy not to be neglected.</p>
            <p n="2">II. They give us a considerable hint, in saying that they are <hi>Legal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Recognized</hi> by the <hi>Parliament;</hi> and thence wou'd infer, that it's a Crime against the Government to accuse them of <hi>Heresie,</hi> which is high<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly punishable by the <hi>Law.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="1">1. But, is not <hi>Turners-Hall</hi> as much <hi>Recognized</hi> and <hi>Tolerated</hi> as <hi>Grace-church-street?</hi> And is not <hi>Apostacy</hi> as grievous a Charge as <hi>Heresie?</hi> And do not the <hi>Grace-church-street Quakers</hi> accuse those of <hi>Turners Hall</hi> for <hi>Apostates?</hi> Let them acquit themselves of this, and at the same time they have cleared <hi>G. K.</hi> and those of <hi>Turners-Hall</hi> from this Charge.</p>
            <p n="2">2. But are not other <hi>Dissenters</hi> as much within the Act of <hi>Tolleration</hi> as the <hi>Quakers?</hi> And how do the <hi>Quakers</hi> treat them? See their Book Entituled <hi>Quakerism a new Nick Name,</hi> &amp;c. p. 165. Where they call them <hi>An ill-bred Pedantick Crew; the bane of Religion, and pest of the World, the old Incendiaries to mischief, and best to be spared of mankind; against whom the boyling Vengeance of an Irritated God is ready to be poured out.</hi> And are such Men as these fit to be <hi>Tolerated!</hi> Are such Men as these fit to be <hi>Recogniz'd</hi> by the <hi>Parliament,</hi> as <hi>Protestants!</hi> What an Odium must this bring upon the very Name of <hi>Protestant,</hi> not only amongst the <hi>Papists,</hi> but with all that call themselves <hi>Christians,</hi> even to the very <hi>Heathen,</hi> and all <hi>mankind,</hi> who will believe this Representation of our <hi>Dissenters,</hi> which is given by the <hi>Quakers!</hi> And what sort of Reflection does this imply upon the <hi>Parliament,</hi> which does <hi>Recognize</hi> these Men as <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>testants,</hi> and make a <hi>Law</hi> on purpose to grant you <hi>Tolleration!</hi> This is Referr'd to the <hi>Committee of Priviledges</hi> to consider.</p>
            <p n="3">3. But let us go a little further. The <hi>Church of</hi> England is not only <hi>Recogniz'd</hi> and <hi>Tolerated,</hi> but <hi>Established</hi> by <hi>Law.</hi> And if regard to <hi>Laws</hi> ought to be observ'd, she might expect some more decent Treatment (upon that account) at the hand of the <hi>Quakers,</hi> who now plead the <hi>Laws</hi> in their Defence. And the common <hi>Epithet</hi> which the <hi>Clergy</hi> of the <hi>Church of</hi> England receives from the <hi>Quakers,</hi> is that of <hi>Baal<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s Priests,</hi> as fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently in <hi>G. Fox</hi>'s <hi>Journal,</hi> and the rest of their Books. And this makes them not only <hi>Hereticks,</hi> but downright <hi>Idolators,</hi> as bad as the very <hi>Heathen.</hi> Nay, the <hi>Quakers</hi> call them <hi>Devils, Conjurers, Thieves, Dogs,
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:36258:6"/> Wolves,</hi> &amp;c. In their <hi>Guide Mistaken,</hi> &amp;c. p. 18. you have this Elegant Description of them, <hi>viz. The Idle Gormandizing Priests of</hi> England, <hi>run a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way with</hi> 150000<hi> l. a Year, under pretence of God's Ministers—And no sort of People have been so universally through Ages, the very Bane of Soul and Body of the Ʋniverse, as that Abominable Tribe, for whom the Theatre of God's most dreadful Vengeance is Reserved, to Act their Eternal Tragedy upon,</hi> &amp;c. And in Excuse for these sort of Expressions, they say again in their <hi>Serious A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>polo<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>y</hi> p. 156. That <hi>had they been ten thousand times more significant, earnest and sharp against that cursed bitter Stock of Hirelings, they had been but enough; and I wou<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>d then say not enough, but that the Reverence I bear to the Holy Spirit</hi> (i. e. in the Quakers) <hi>wou'd oblige me to aquiesce in whatever he shou'd utter through any Prophet, or Servant of the Lord,</hi> i. e. the <hi>Quakers Prophets,</hi> who vented these <hi>soft</hi> Expressions against the <hi>Clergy</hi> of the <hi>Church of England;</hi> which it seems needed an <hi>Apology</hi> for the <hi>Quakers Aquiescing</hi> in such, and not inventing more <hi>sharp,</hi> which I suppose all the <hi>Furies</hi> in <hi>Hell</hi> cou'd not help them to. But being so stinted to <hi>Mildness,</hi> the aforesaid Author goes on, <hi>(ibid.)</hi> against the <hi>Cler<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>y</hi> thus. <hi>And we have nothing for them but</hi> Woes <hi>and</hi> Plagues, <hi>who have made Drunk the Nations, and laid them to sleep on Downy Beds of soft Sin, pleasing Principles, whilst they have cut their Purses, and pick'd their Pockets; Tophets prepar'd for them to Act their Eternal Tragedy upon, whose Scenes will be renewed Direful, Anguishing</hi> Woes <hi>of an Eternal Irreconcileable Justice.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And they make an <hi>Excuse,</hi> for not saying <hi>ten thousand times more signifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cant, earnest and sharp</hi> Invectives against the <hi>Church of England;</hi> and say, that if they cou'd, all wou'd be too little for them. We are much obliged to them for their Love! But where is their Reverence for <hi>Laws,</hi> with which they so much Press <hi>G. Keith,</hi> for Invading (as they pretend) the <hi>Act of Toleration,</hi> in Accusing them of <hi>Heresie?</hi> While they make no Ce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>remony of Ramming all the <hi>Church of England</hi> into <hi>Hell,</hi> and are sorry they cannot find a Place <hi>ten thousand</hi> times worse for them; and take no Account at all of their being <hi>Establish'd</hi> by <hi>Law;</hi> or of their being <hi>Free-born English-men,</hi> which they Plead as their Security, to <hi>hide</hi> and <hi>cover</hi> them from <hi>G. Keith,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p n="4">4. But tho' they Appeal to the <hi>Laws,</hi> when they seem to Favour them, yet, if in any thing they go Counter to the least of their <hi>Principles,</hi> they Damn both <hi>Laws,</hi> and <hi>Law makers,</hi> and all who dare <hi>own</hi> or <hi>obey</hi> any such <hi>Laws.</hi> Thus when <hi>Laws</hi> were made for the Payment of <hi>Tythes</hi> to the <hi>Clergy,</hi> the <hi>Quakers</hi> boldly declar'd such <hi>Laws</hi> to be <hi>Null,</hi> and <hi>Void,</hi> Damn'd the <hi>Law makers</hi> for <hi>Devils,</hi> and all such as should Obey them. And this ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears under the Hands of above <hi>seven Thousand</hi> of them, Printed, 1659. under this Title. <hi>These several Papers were sent to the Parliament, the</hi> 20th. <hi>day of the</hi> 5th. <hi>Month,</hi> 1659. <hi>being above seven Thousand of the Names of the Hand maids, and Daughters of the Lord, and such as feel the Oppression of
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:36258:6"/> Tythes,</hi> &amp;c. And the like was Subscrib'd by many more <hi>Thousands</hi> of the <hi>Men Quakers;</hi> and all Approv'd and Directed by their Great Apostle <hi>G. Fox.</hi> In the abovesaid Book, p. 3. they say, <hi>The Commands of Men must be Annulled, that take Tythes, and not to be Obey'd by them that live in the Covenant of God,</hi> and p. 21. <hi>Therefore we with our Names and Hands, bear our Testimony against Tythes, the giver of them, the setter of them up, and the ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ker of them,</hi> and p. 63. <hi>We Declare with our Hands, and with our Lives and Estates, against the Ministry that takes Tythes,—and the</hi> Law <hi>that upholds them.</hi> and p. 71. <hi>Are not all these set up by the</hi> Dragon's <hi>Power, and held up by the Dragon's Power, the Devourer, the Destroyer? Is not this the Power of the Devil?</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>Here the <hi>Parliament</hi> are the <hi>Dragon</hi> and the <hi>Dev<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>l!</hi> and they Engage their <hi>Lives</hi> and <hi>Estates,</hi> in a <hi>Solemn League and Covenant</hi> against them, and their <hi>Laws;</hi> which <hi>Laws</hi> they now hold up as a <hi>Buckler</hi> to Shild them from the Force of <hi>G. Keith.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="5">5. But they proceed further than all this. They not only Condemn <hi>Laws,</hi> when they are against them; but they Declare against all <hi>Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stracy,</hi> except in their own Hands; but especially against that of <hi>Kings. The Lord is Risen</hi> (says <hi>Edward Burrough,</hi> in his <hi>Standard,</hi> &amp;c p. 9.) <hi>To o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verturn, overturn Kings and Princes, and Governments, and Laws; and he will change Times, and Laws, and Governments. There shall be no King, but Iesus, nor no Government of Force, but the Government of the Lamb.</hi> i. e. of the <hi>Quakers,</hi> who think themselves only to be in his Power. <hi>G. Fox</hi> in his <hi>A Word from the Lord.</hi> p. 15. Say's, <hi>There is that Nature that wou'd have an Earthly King to Reign, in which Nature lodgeth the Murtherer.</hi> And in a Book of his, which bears this Title, <hi>Several Papers given forth by</hi> George Fox. Printed, 1660. He say's, p 8. <hi>All Kings and Emperors have sprung up in the Night, since the days of the Apostles among the Antichrists.</hi> and p. 12. <hi>So the Christians go out from Christ, and set up Kings, like the Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>then.</hi> p. 16. <hi>We know that the</hi> Kings <hi>are the Spiritual</hi> Aegyptians, <hi>got up since the days of the Apostles.</hi>—p. 9. and 18. <hi>You never Read of any</hi> (King) <hi>among the Christians, but among the Apostates, since the days of the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles.</hi>— p. 8. <hi>Many cry for an Earthly King, and will have</hi> Caesar, <hi>and is not this the same nature the</hi> Jews <hi>was in? And do not they in this Crucifie</hi> Jesus?—p. 9. <hi>Are not all these Christians, that will d<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>te so much of an Earthly King,</hi> Traytors <hi>against</hi> Christ? <hi>And will these that are true Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stians, have any more Kings among them, but Christ?—I say that is the False Church that doth not live—upon the Heads of the Kings,</hi> &amp;c, <hi>i. e.</hi> in their <hi>Cant,</hi> to trample them under their Feet. <hi>The Lord will clear the Land of you</hi> (Rulers, Priests, <hi>&amp;c.) and not any that Rejects Christ, shall Rule in</hi> England. Say they, in <hi>Discovery of Enmity,</hi> &amp;c. p. 29. Now whether they do not think that all <hi>Church of</hi> England-<hi>men</hi> do <hi>Reject Christ;</hi> they have shewn in the above <hi>Epithets,</hi> which they have given of them: and
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:36258:7"/> that they think the same of all others, but themselves, see <hi>The Snake Grass.</hi> 2d. Edi. <hi>Sect.</hi> 16. p. 189.</p>
            <p>Thus much for <hi>Kings.</hi> And now for the Remainder of the Constitution of our Government, the next, is <hi>the House of Lords.</hi> Towards whom <hi>G. Fox</hi> shews h<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>s Respect in a Paper, which he directs <hi>To the Council of Officers of the Army,</hi> &amp;c, Printed, 1659. Where Exulting in the Victories of the <hi>Saints</hi> against the <hi>King,</hi> among other Marks of their <hi>Holiness,</hi> and to Guard against Returning to the Old Constitution of <hi>King, Lords,</hi> &amp;c. Which then begain to Threaten the <hi>Ʋsurpers,</hi> and towards which he fear'd some of them did too much incline; he minds them of their former <hi>Glorious Rebellion,</hi> and says, p. 7. <hi>Oh what a Sincerity was once in the Nation! What a Dirty Nasty thing it wou'd have been, to have heard of a House of Lords among them!</hi> Thus Civilly do's he make his Court to their Lordships.</p>
            <p>Now for the whole <hi>Parliament,</hi> the <hi>Quakers</hi> make as Bold with them, and Preach up the Lawfulness of the <hi>Peoples</hi> (whom they call their <hi>Masters</hi>) taking Arms against them, and turning them out of Doors. Thus says <hi>Francis Howgil</hi> in his <hi>Information, and also Advice to the Army,</hi> &amp;c. p. 5. <hi>Many</hi> (says he) <hi>are so Doating on the Name of a</hi> Parliament, <hi>as tho' it were Essential, and cries up</hi> Priviledge of Parliament. <hi>But if they will not hearken to the Voice of their</hi> Masters <hi>the</hi> People, <hi>but may be call them Rebels and Tray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, if the shou'd be turned out,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>How luckily now have the <hi>Quakers</hi> brought in the <hi>Laws</hi> of the Land, in their Aid against <hi>G. Keith,</hi> as if themselves were wholly Innocent in this Matter! But they have thereby given occasion for very Necessary and Important Considerations to be had upon this Head. But I proceed.</p>
            <p n="3">III. They Accuse <hi>G. Keith</hi> of a Design to Invade their <hi>Property,</hi> in Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging them with such a <hi>Penal</hi> Crime as <hi>Heresie;</hi> and to raise a <hi>Persecution</hi> against them.</p>
            <p>This is a Pitiful and a Guilty Plea; And the proper Defence had been to have Appear'd and Justified themselves. But to hide themselves under <hi>Acts of Parliament,</hi> being <hi>Free-born English-men,</hi> and securing of their <hi>Property's,</hi> is flying out of the Pit, and calling for Help from the By-standers, which is yielding up the Cause to all Intents and Purposes; and leaving their <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>querors</hi> to <hi>Triumph,</hi> without any Opposition.</p>
            <p>But it serves for other Ends, which they little dream'd of, even to call their own Sins to Remembrance. For they Accus'd <hi>G. Keith</hi> of this same Crime of <hi>Heresie,</hi> for Preaching of an outward <hi>Christ,</hi> besides their <hi>Light within,</hi> which they call'd Preaching of <hi>two Christ's.</hi> And they Prosecuted him for this, and Proceeded even to an Accusation against his Life. As you may see in the Printed Tryals of him, and others in <hi>Pensilvania;</hi> and in a Book Intituled, <hi>The Heresie and Hatred, which was Falsly Charg'd upon the Innocent, Justly Return'd upon the Guilty,</hi> &amp;c. Printed at <hi>Philadel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phia,</hi> 1693.</p>
            <pb n="11" facs="tcp:36258:7"/>
            <p>But with what Face cou'd these Men Accuse <hi>G. Keith</hi> for Invading of <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perty,</hi> whose Avowed <hi>Principles</hi> are to the Destruction of the <hi>Property's</hi> of others? As in the Case of <hi>Tythes,</hi> which are as much the <hi>Property</hi> of the <hi>Clergy,</hi> Confirm'd by <hi>Acts of Parliament,</hi> as any Man's Estate in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And not only in <hi>Tythes,</hi> wherein they pretend some Scruple of <hi>Consci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence;</hi> for their <hi>Conscience</hi> extends likewise to other Mens <hi>Houses</hi> and <hi>Lands. G. Fox,</hi> in his <hi>fifty nine Particulars,</hi> which he sent <hi>to the Parliament of the Common-wealth of</hi> England, Printed, 1659. p. 8. the 32. Particular is in these Words. <hi>Let all those Fines that belong to Lords of Mannors, be given to the poor People, for Lords have enough.</hi> And Particular 29. <hi>Let all those Ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by lands, Gleab lands that is given to the Priests, be given to the Poor of the Nation; and let all the great Houses, Abby's, Steeple houses</hi> (this is the Name they give, in scorn, to our Churches) <hi>and White-hall be for Alms-houses, for the Blind and Lame to be th<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>re,</hi> &amp;c. Here <hi>White hall</hi> must go too, as well as the <hi>Fines</hi> of <hi>Lords of Mannors.</hi> And in the foremention'd Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dress to the same Parliament, 1659. Subscrib'd by above <hi>seven Thousand</hi> of the <hi>Quakers,</hi> p. 59. 63. and 65. they Require that the <hi>late King</hi> (as these <hi>Rebels</hi> Stil'd him) his <hi>Rents, Parks,</hi> and <hi>Houses</hi> shou'd be Sold, and all the <hi>Colledges,</hi> and their <hi>Lands.</hi> And the very <hi>Bells</hi> out of the <hi>Churches,</hi> except <hi>one in a Town, to give notice of Fire,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>This was no Invading of <hi>Property</hi> in them! But for <hi>G. Keith,</hi> or any other to Detect their <hi>Errors,</hi> this is Encroaching upon their <hi>Property,</hi> as <hi>English men!</hi> And no less than a direct <hi>Persecution!</hi> And therefore they cry out upon the <hi>Brachium seculare,</hi> the <hi>Temporal Laws</hi> to come in to their Rescue. Of which they have so often and loudly complained against others, as a <hi>Popish</hi> Principle, to Answer by such <hi>Inquisitions,</hi> instead of <hi>Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guments.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But let us compare this Terrible <hi>Persecution</hi> of <hi>G. Keith,</hi> with what the <hi>Quakers</hi> have Preach'd up, and that in the <hi>Name of the Lord,</hi> against others. <hi>George Bishop,</hi> in his <hi>Warnings of the Lord,</hi> &amp;c. Printed, 1660. p. 19. Cry's out to the <hi>Officers of the Army, Remember</hi> Amalek, <hi>that is</hi> (says he) <hi>the Soul Murthering, and Conscience-binding Clergy man bl<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> out the Remembrance of</hi> Amalek <hi>from under Heaven— ye shall not forget it.</hi> And of the <hi>Lawyers</hi> he say's, <hi>Vex the</hi> Midianites, <hi>for they Vex you with their Wiles.</hi> And <hi>G. Fox,</hi> in <hi>News out of the North.</hi> p. 31. Proclaims thus, <hi>Slay</hi> Baal, Balaam <hi>must be Slain, and all the</hi> Hirelings <hi>must be turn'd out of the Kingdom.</hi> These are their common <hi>Epithets</hi> for the <hi>Clergy.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And in his <hi>Papists Strength,</hi> &amp;c. Printed, 1658. p. 19. he says. <hi>And this I Declare in the Presence of the Lord God, and all the Magistrates that be in God's Fear, they will break down the Mass houses, Schools, and Colledges, which you make Priests and Ministers in.</hi> This was to pull down the <hi>Nests,</hi> that the <hi>Rooks</hi> might be Banished. But they were not to Escape so well: For <hi>oh</hi>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:36258:8"/> (says <hi>Edward Burrough,</hi> in his <hi>Word of Advice to the Souldiers,</hi> p. 2.) <hi>Give the Priests Blood to drink, for they are worthy!</hi> This was Comfortable <hi>Advice</hi> to <hi>Souldiers!</hi> They are ready <hi>Executioners!</hi> When thus <hi>Holloo'd</hi> by <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets</hi> sent from the <hi>Lord,</hi> as they pretended. <hi>Slay</hi> Balaam! <hi>vex the</hi> Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dianites! <hi>Root out the Remembrance of</hi> Amalek <hi>from under Heaven! Give the</hi> Priests <hi>Blood to drink, turn the</hi> Hirelings <hi>out of the Kingdom!</hi> Here was no Design of <hi>Persecution,</hi> or Hurting of any Man's <hi>Property!</hi> or of <hi>Reviling,</hi> and Blemishing the <hi>Reputation</hi> of <hi>Free born</hi> English-men; and Exposing them to the <hi>Fury</hi> of the <hi>Mob! To the Scorn, Contempt, and Rage of a mixt Mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titude, who are Ʋnmeet to Judge of Religious and Spiritual Matters or Contro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>versies,</hi> as the <hi>Quakers</hi> Urge against <hi>G. Keith.</hi> But it seems that they thought <hi>common Souldiers</hi> were good and sufficient <hi>Judges</hi> of <hi>Controversy. G. Fox</hi> Addresses his sweet Paper, (before mentioned) not only <hi>To the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil of Officers of the Army, and the Heads of the Nation,</hi> but <hi>for the Inferior Officers and Souldiers to Read,</hi> as it is Worded in the Direction.</p>
            <p n="4">IV. But perhaps the <hi>Quakers</hi> have chang'd their Mind since those Times; and are now become more <hi>Sober,</hi> and <hi>Peaceable</hi> in their Dispositions; I hope so of many of them. But then this is against the Will and Direction of their <hi>Leaders</hi> and <hi>Rulers.</hi> For since all the late Objections which have been made against them, both as to their <hi>Errors</hi> in <hi>Faith,</hi> and their vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent <hi>Persecuting Principles,</hi> they have in their last <hi>Yearly Meeting</hi> in <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> 1696. Re-asserted the whole; that none may think they are chang'd in the least Tittle. For in the <hi>Yearly Epistle,</hi> then given forth, and Printed, they Exhort all the <hi>Quakers,</hi> not to be mov'd at all the Objections against their Ancient <hi>Doctors,</hi> or to think them to have been <hi>Fallible</hi> (for then down must come their whole Foundation) but to stand stiff to their Tackle, or, as they word it, to <hi>hold up the Holy Testimony of Truth, which hath made us</hi> (says that Decretory Epistle) <hi>a People to God, and preserved us so unto this Day; annd that in all the Parts of it: For Truth is one, and changes not; and what it Convinced us of to be Evil in the beginning, it Reproves still.</hi> i. e. The <hi>Church of</hi> England, and all our <hi>Magistrates, Kings, Lords,</hi> and <hi>Commons,</hi> to be <hi>Serpents, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vils, Scarlet-coulored-beasts,</hi> &amp;c. And they Maintain their <hi>Ancient Testi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miny,</hi> and that, <hi>in all the parts of it.</hi> For, <hi>Truth is one, and changes not.</hi> i. e. The <hi>Quakers</hi> who are, and always have been in the <hi>Truth,</hi> have not <hi>Changed</hi> at all since the <hi>Beginning.</hi> So that by this, they have made themselves Answerable for all that they have said since their <hi>Begin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Add in that <hi>Yearly Epistle,</hi> mention is made of <hi>Deputations</hi> sent thither from <hi>Barbadoes. Mary-land, West-jersey, Pensilvania, Burmudoes, Antegua, Holland, Ireland,</hi> and <hi>Scotland,</hi> which shews the Extent of their Dominions. And this <hi>Yearly Epistle</hi> goes through all these; and Engages the whole Body of the <hi>Quakers.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="5">
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:36258:8"/>V. Now the Application which it is Rational to make of all this, is, That these <hi>Quakers</hi> having not fewer than a <hi>thousand</hi> Meetings in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land;</hi> which, by computing but a Hundred to a Meeting, one with an other, will amount to one <hi>Hundred Thousand</hi> in <hi>England alone,</hi> besides all the Countries above-nam'd. It is therefore very reasonable that so great a Body shou'd not be neglected, especially considering, that they are grown very <hi>Wealthy,</hi> and are the most compacted in their <hi>Government</hi> and <hi>Discipline</hi> of any <hi>Community</hi> that is amongst us.</p>
            <p>And if they are such irreconcilable Enemies to our <hi>Church</hi> and <hi>Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment,</hi> as their <hi>Ancient Testimonies</hi> do hold forth, they must be extrem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly dangerous.</p>
            <p>But if they are as <hi>Heterodox</hi> in the <hi>Christian Faith,</hi> as the Quotations out of their Books (which they do not deny) do testifie, then it will be an Horrible Scandal to our Religion to have them Recogniz'd as <hi>Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stants;</hi> and will give the <hi>Papists</hi> such an handle against us, as we shall not be able to withstand.</p>
            <p>Therefore the least that can be expected from them, is, to appear be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore such Person or Persons as shall be thereunto appointed by Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty; and there Publickly, and under their Hands, to <hi>Disown, Renounce,</hi> and <hi>Condemn,</hi> in such <hi>Positive</hi> and <hi>Express</hi> Terms as shall be prescrib<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d to them, all the above <hi>Ignominious</hi> and <hi>Bloody</hi> Quotations out of their Books, and such others as shall be fully prov'd against them; together with the <hi>Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thors</hi> of them, as not only <hi>Fallible,</hi> but <hi>Erroneous</hi> and <hi>Wicked Teachers,</hi> at least, in all those Points which shall be so prov'd against them.</p>
            <p>And if they shall refuse to do this, then can they not, with any Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stice, complain (tho' complain they wou'd) if the <hi>Parliament</hi> did recall their including them within the Number of <hi>Protestants;</hi> it being other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wise Impossible to Retrieve the Reputation of the Name of <hi>Protestant;</hi> or give any tolerable Security to the <hi>Government.</hi> And a less Satisfacti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on cannot be expected, for all the <hi>dreadful</hi> and <hi>odious Characters</hi> given of the <hi>Bishops</hi> and <hi>Church of England</hi> than a Retractation of them; and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledging that the same were not given forth by the <hi>Holy Spirit</hi> of <hi>God,</hi> as these <hi>Quakers</hi> have <hi>Blaspemously</hi> pretended.</p>
            <p>And their Modern Advocate <hi>W. C.</hi> under the disguise of a <hi>moderate Church Man,</hi> cannot desire fairer Terms for them, unless he will throw off his <hi>Vizard,</hi> and declare himself as great an Enemy to the <hi>Church of England</hi> as themselves.</p>
            <pb n="14" facs="tcp:36258:9"/>
            <p>There is no Medium: He that has said <hi>vile</hi> and <hi>scandalous</hi> things of a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother, must either <hi>unsay,</hi> or <hi>stand by it,</hi> and <hi>justifie</hi> it. And the lookers on have leave to think the <hi>Accusation</hi> just against those, who are con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent to sit with it, and dare not insist upon so small a <hi>Satisfaction</hi> as a bare <hi>Acknowledgement:</hi> But when (without this, or any sign of <hi>Repentance</hi>) they <hi>Court</hi> those who have <hi>Abus'd</hi> them, and seek to engage them by new <hi>Favours,</hi> 'tis not only a <hi>servile Truckling;</hi> but when others are concern'd as well as themselves, their <hi>Predecessors,</hi> their <hi>Successors,</hi> their whole <hi>Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der,</hi> and the Cause of <hi>Religion</hi> and <hi>Christianity</hi> with them, it is most <hi>un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>just,</hi> and betraying of their <hi>Trust;</hi> it is letting of their <hi>Flocks</hi> go to the <hi>Wolves,</hi> and giving them their <hi>Pass.</hi> When the <hi>Honour</hi> of <hi>Religion</hi> is once Prostituted, its <hi>Power</hi> and <hi>Influence</hi> will soon decay.</p>
            <p n="6">VI. But the <hi>Quakers</hi> have the least reason of any <hi>Dissenters</hi> to expect the <hi>Bishops</hi> or <hi>Church of</hi> England's concurrance in granting <hi>them Tolleration:</hi> They having exceeded all others in <hi>Rancor,</hi> not only against the <hi>Bishops Persons,</hi> but against <hi>Episcopacy</hi> it self. For when the <hi>Baptists</hi> had said, they thought it their <hi>Duty to preserve them</hi> (the Bishops and Clergy) <hi>from all violence,</hi> &amp;c. The <hi>Quakers</hi> assaulted them from all Quarters, even for so much tenderness towards the <hi>Bishops,</hi> as to preserve their <hi>Persons</hi> from <hi>Violence</hi> and <hi>Injury,</hi> much more to think of granting them any <hi>Tolleration, Ed. Burrough</hi> one of the <hi>Principal,</hi> and most <hi>Primitive Pillars</hi> of the <hi>Quakers Church,</hi> wrot a Tract on purpose against this <hi>Declaration</hi> of the <hi>Anabaptists,</hi> and says to them (p. 618. of his <hi>Works,</hi> printed 1672.) <hi>What, are you about to make a League and Covenant with Antichrist? — Do you look upon them to be Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nisters of Christ or of Antichrist? — Is not not this a league with Hell and Death? And p.</hi> 619. <hi>Wha<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> are you now for Tollerating Episcopacy? And if Episcopacy, why may not Popery be Tollera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted? Seeing they are one and the self-same in Ground and Nature,</hi> &amp;c. He was seconded by another of great Name among the <hi>Quaker Worthies, Rich. Hubberthorn</hi> who attacked this Declaration of the <hi>Anabaptists</hi> in the same strain (p. 229. of his <hi>Works,</hi> printed 1663.) <hi>Why will you not Tollerate Popery</hi> (says he) <hi>as well as Episcopacy? Have not the Professors of Episco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacy Murdered and Slain, and do labor to Murder and Slay the People of God as well as the Papists? and will you Tollerate the</hi> Common Prayer <hi>among the Episcopacy, and not the</hi> Mass Book <hi>among the Papist, seeing that the</hi> Mass <hi>was the Substance out of which the</hi> Common Prayer <hi>was Extract<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> And much more to the same Purpose, in these and others of their Writers.</p>
            <p>And if they will not now <hi>Retract</hi> these, and own them a <hi>false Principles,</hi> they must ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther think that the <hi>Church</hi> of <hi>England</hi> do's approve of their <hi>Doctrines</hi> to be truly <hi>Christi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>an;</hi> or otherwise, that She commits a great <hi>Sin</hi> in granting <hi>Tolleration</hi> to them. None have a Right to expect <hi>Tolleration</hi> from others, but They, whose Principle it is to grant <hi>Tolleration</hi> to those others, when they are in the Power. For</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Whatsoever ye would that Men should do unto you, do ye even so unno them.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But there is an <hi>Exception,</hi> as to the <hi>Quakers,</hi> in this Case; for, as told before, they De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clare against all <hi>Kings</hi> and <hi>Governments</hi> upon <hi>Earth.</hi> Why? Because they will have no <hi>King</hi> but <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>: Of which they have given Publick notice in what they Stile <hi>A Declarati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> the People called</hi> Quakers, <hi>to the present D<gap reason="illegible: missing" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>acted Nation of</hi> England, <hi>printed</hi> 1659. Where in p. 8 and 9. They <hi>Proclaim,</hi> That they <hi>have chosen the Son of God to be their King; and that He hath chosen them to be His People:</hi> And thence infer, That as it is <hi>His</hi> only <hi>Right to Rule in Nations</hi> (whence they supersede the Commission of all other <hi>Kings</hi> or <hi>Rulers</hi>) so is it, say they, <hi>Our</hi> Heirship to <hi>Possess the uttermost Parts of the Earth;</hi> and that He may Command them to <hi>Fight</hi> in this Cause, to Regain <hi>His Right</hi> and <hi>Theirs,</hi> which is <hi>Usurp'd</hi> from them, Therefore, tho' they may expect <hi>Toleration</hi> from others, yet ought they not to grant it to others; Because all other<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> are <hi>Usurpers</hi> of the <hi>Power</hi> which they <hi>Possess:</hi> And theirs <hi>O<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ly</hi> is the <hi>Heirship</hi> to Possess not only <hi>England,</hi> but <hi>the uttermost Parts of the Earth.</hi> For which they have <hi>Declar'd</hi> it their <hi>Principle</hi> to <hi>Fight.</hi> Nor will they <hi>Retract</hi> this <hi>Secret of</hi> their <hi>Government.</hi> Let this be the <hi>Test.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <date>May 8. 1697.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:36258:9"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>